hasura instantly turn your relational database into a graphql or rest api
hasura 在构建全栈应用程序时立即将您的关系数据库转换为 graphql 或 rest api
when building a full stack application the end user likely needs to communicate
最终用户可能需要
with a database that means you need to build a secure
与数据库通信，这意味着您需要在中间构建一个安全的
api in the middle so the client can tell the server what it needs from the
api，以便客户端可以告诉服务器它需要什么 从
database but building the perfect api is easier said than done front-end
数据库构建完美的api 说起来容易做
developers love using graphql but back-end developers are faced with the
起来难 前端开发人员喜欢使用 graphql，但后端开发人员
challenge of writing efficient sql queries that resolve the
面临着编写高效的 sql 查询来解决
graphql schema the hasura engine eliminates this problem
graphql 模式的挑战 hasura 引擎
by automatically generating the schema and resolvers for you
通过自动生成 架构和解析器
just point it to your postgres database and it will use the existing tables and
只需将其指向您的 postgres 数据库，它将使用现有的表和
views to generate an api that's ready to roll in your frontend app if you don't
视图生成一个 api，如果您还
already have a database you can connect one from anywhere in the cloud
没有数据库，您可以从任何地方连接到您的前端应用程序中 云
then add tables and rows to it and manage all of your data directly from
然后向其中添加表和行并直接从 Web ui 管理所有数据
the web ui and it can even help you configure
，它甚至可以帮助您配置
relationships between tables in addition to databases you can also
关系 b 除了数据库之外的表之间，您还可以
connect third-party apis to your schema to create a single source of truth for
将第三方 API 连接到您的架构，以便为您的所有数据创建单一事实来源。
all your data in some cases you may want to extend the schema with your own
在某些情况下，您可能希望使用自己的
custom queries or mutations actions provide a way to implement
自定义查询或突变操作来扩展架构
custom business logic in an external server or serverless function
在外部服务器或无服务器函数中实现自定义业务逻辑，
to read and write data in more complex ways in addition
以更复杂的方式读取和写入数据此外，
you may want to trigger server-side code when something changes in the database
您可能希望在数据库发生更改时触发服务器端代码，
like you may want to send a transactional email when a new row is
例如您可能希望在新行发生时发送事务性电子邮件 被
added to a certain table hassura events can be triggered based on operations to
添加到某个表 hassura 事件可以基于对某个表的操作触发，也可以
a certain table or scheduled with a cron job in the
在后台使用 cron 作业进行调度，
background but one thing hysura doesn't handle
但是 hysura 不处理的一件事
is user authentication although you can easily connect your favorite
是用户身份验证，尽管您可以轻松连接您最喜欢的
authentication service and provide a role session variable when the user
身份验证服务并提供用户发出请求时的角色会话变量，
makes requests which can then be used to implement
现在可以通过单击按钮来实现
role-based access control with the click of a button
基于角色的访问控制
now because the api is created with an industry standard like graphql
因为 api 是使用像 graphql 这样的行业标准创建的，所以
you can use any graphql client that you'd like to access the data on the
您可以使用任何您想在前端访问数据的 graphql 客户
front end you might use something like apollo
端，您可以使用像 apollo 这样的东西
to query mutate and set up real-time subscriptions to your database
来查询 mutate 并设置对数据库
in other words hasura is kind of like a middleman that doesn't care what you use
的实时订阅 换句话说，hasura 有点像一个中间人，它不关心你
on the front end or where you host your actual database
在前端使用什么或者你在哪里托管你的实际数据库
and best of all it's an open source project that can be self-hosted
，最重要的是它是一个开源项目，可以自托管
or paid for as a fully managed service with a free tier
或作为完全托管的付费项目提供免费
this has been hasura in 100 seconds if you want to see more short videos like
套餐的服务，这已经在 100 秒内完成了如果您想看到更多这样的短视频，
this make sure to hit the like button and let
请务必点击“喜欢”按钮，
me know if you want to see a full tutorial on this topic in the comments
如果您想在评论中看到有关此主题的完整教程，请告诉我
thanks for watching and i will see you in the next one
谢谢收看 我会在下一个见到你